<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

	<title>Otávio Pires's Blog</title>
	<link href="http://otaviopires.github.io/blog/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
	<link href="http://otaviopires.github.io/blog"/>
	<updated>2016-03-09T20:17:43-03:00</updated>
	<id>http://otaviopires.github.io/blog</id>
	<author>
		<name>Otávio Pires</name>
		<email>otavio.silva.pires@gmail.com</email>
	</author>

	
		<entry>
			<title>Estudando Scrum</title>
			<link href="http://otaviopires.github.io/blog/2016/03/09/scrum"/>
			<updated>2016-03-09T00:00:00-03:00</updated>
			<id>http://otaviopires.github.io//blog/2016/03/09/scrum</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Visão geral&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Esse vídeo aqui &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XfvQWnRgxG0&quot;&gt;(Aprenda Scrum em 9 minutos)&lt;/a&gt; é muito bom para uma visão geral, um “handshake” com o framework, entender melhor do que se trata, se é útil pra você, se irá se encaixar nas suas necessidades e tudo mais…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- [![IMAGE ALT TEXT HERE](http://img.youtube.com/vi/XfvQWnRgxG0/0.jpg)](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XfvQWnRgxG0)
 --&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Curso aprofundado&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Já esse outro vídeo aqui: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iMS5U0EiGFs&quot;&gt;Aula 1 - Abertura do Curso de Scrum - 100 Lero Lero, &lt;/a&gt;
 é o início de uma série, em formato de curso mesmo, que vai te dar uma visão aprofundada do assunto, te pegando pela mão e explicando o que é necessário para aplicar o Scrum e já começar a usá-lo rapidamente. Porque afinal de contas se você está estudando isso é porquê está com muita pressa pra realizar algum projeto, não é?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Não gostei muito desse curso. O cara não ensina muito bem, e trata-se claramente de apenas uma tradução do &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scrumguides.org/docs/scrumguide/v1/Scrum-Guide-US.pdf&quot;&gt;The Scrum Guide™&lt;/a&gt; oficial do site &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scrumalliance.org&quot;&gt;scrumalliance.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nesse &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scrumalliance.org&quot;&gt;site&lt;/a&gt; do Scrum tem um ótimo &lt;a href=&quot;http://fast.wistia.net/embed/iframe/p7novk9lc6&quot;&gt;vídeo&lt;/a&gt; introdutório, bem melhor que os acima.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Carl James Says Everything</title>
			<link href="http://otaviopires.github.io/blog/2016/03/08/carl-james-says-the-truth"/>
			<updated>2016-03-08T00:00:00-03:00</updated>
			<id>http://otaviopires.github.io//blog/2016/03/08/carl-james-says-the-truth</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Quoted from the book Business Model You by Alexander Osterwalder, Tim Clark, and Yves Pigneur:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The company I started did research and market entry consulting for companies wanting to enter Asian markets, particularly Japan. After more than six years of ferociously hard work, we received a multi-million-dollar buyout offer. This was all new to me; when I started, I didn’t even know people sold companies.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Anyway, I paid off three mortgages, maxed out the kids’ college funds, took the family on a great vacation, and invested the remainder to provide passive income. But like everyone else, I still faced the big question: What am I going to do with the rest of my life?
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
In a way, that question grew tougher precisely because I’d been relieved of the pressing need to earn a living. Seeking answers sharpened my awareness that work is about more than achieving financial independence.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I think most successful entrepreneurs feel the same way. I’ve talked with a lot of people who collectively have sold dozens of companies for amounts ranging from one to $40 million U.S. Not a single one ever mentioned “achieving financial independence” as their primary motivation for working.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Fortune-seekers can rarely sustain their passion through the hard times. Successful enterprises are laser-focused on Value Provided to Customers. Entrepreneurship is not about you; it’s about effectively serving others.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 — Carl James, Entrepreneur&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This testimony hit me like a rock!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not about you, it’s all about serving others. Providing great service to other people. Giving value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are seeking money or financial freedom, you’ll never gonna get it! It’s a endless road to dissatisfaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find the one thing that you do with pleasure, even when times are harsh, and do it for the people, with passion and love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the rest comes with time.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Otávio Pires, Launches Site</title>
			<link href="http://otaviopires.github.io/blog/2016/03/06/otavio-pires-site-launched"/>
			<updated>2016-03-06T00:00:00-03:00</updated>
			<id>http://otaviopires.github.io//blog/2016/03/06/otavio-pires-site-launched</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well. Finally got around to putting this old website together. Neat thing about it - powered by &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; and I can use Markdown to author my posts. It actually is a lot easier than I thought it was going to be.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	

</feed>
